# **Yogesh Sunil** Mane

# Senior **Automation QA** Engineer

- yogeshmane008@gmail. com
- **\** 7420082526
- Pune, India

### **PROFILE**

Professional Automation Test Engineer overall with 7 **years** of strong experience in Test Automation using Selenium with Java BDD Cucumber Framework as well as **Manual Testing** in Agile Methodology. Good knowledge of **Software** Development Life Cycle and **Software Testing Life Cycle.** 

# **SKILLS**

Selenium WebDriver with Java | Maven | BDD Cucumber Gherkin Page Object Model TestNG | GIT | GitHub | Azure | Bugzilla | Browser Stack (Compatibility Testing) POSTMAN (API Testing)

# EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer **Application,** Maeer's MIT-School of Management College, Pune 2013 - 2016 | Pune, India

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Senior Automation Engineer, Capgemini

05/2024 - present | Pune, India

- Worked in the Financial Industry.
- I worked on both manual and automation using Selenium with Java BDD Cucumber Framework.
- Strong Experience in Automating Web Applications using Selenium WebDriver with TestNG, Maven & BDD(Cucumber).
- Well-acquainted with all phases of **SDLC** & **STLC**.
- Experience in preparing Cucumber feature **files**(User Stories) and automating the **Feature file** using Selenium.
- Used **GitHub**, a Source Code Management tool for code re-usage, high portability, and extending the scope of Automation Testing.
- Good Experience handling **GIT** commands.
- Experience in Java Programming, Selenium WebDriver, and TestNG.
- Hands-on experience in **Agile Methodology**.
- · Attending defect triaging calls and meetings on a daily basis with developers.

#### Senior Automation Engineer,

Volkswagen Information Technology 03/2023 - 12/2023 | Pune, India

- Worked as an Automation Test Engineer for the Automobile Industry.
- Worked on Automation as well as Manual Testing.
- Developed and maintained automated Test scripts using Selenium WebDriver and Java.
- Used TestNG for Test case writing & Test Case Execution.
- Managed source code and version control using
- Involved in **Test planning**, **Requirement Analysis**, Test Case Design, Test Case Execution, and Defect Tracking.
- Skilled in using **Azure** for creating and executing test cases, as well as tracking and resolving defects.
- UAT Support, Performed Ad-hoc Testing, System Testing, and Regression Testing
- Worked in Agile Methodology.

#### Senior Associate QA Engineer,

Beyondwalls Technologies 11/2021 – 11/2022 | Pune, India

- Involvement in the System **Test Plan Preparation** and Requirements Streamlining.
- Involvement in the preparation of **Test Scenarios**, Test Cases, and Test Data.
- Responsible for **GUI** and **Functional Testing**, using Black box Testing Techniques.
- Involvement in Test Execution, Results Analysis, and **Defect Reporting**.
- Involved in Automation Infrastructure Development using **Selenium with Java.**

### **CERTIFICATES**

• Completed Automation Testing course from Qspider's Institute, Pune

# **S** LANGUAGES

English | Hindi | Marathi

- Utilized **TestNG** for test case management and execution.
- Managed source code and version control using GIT.
- Execution of Tests and Reporting Defects to the Dev Team.
- Involved in **Regression Testing** using Selenium

#### Associate QA Engineer,

FarmERP Software Technologies 07/2019 – 11/2021 | Pune, India

- Generating Test Scenarios and Test Cases by referring to Software Requirement Specification documents.
- Involved in **Tests Execution**, **Root Cause Analysis** & **Reporting Defects**.
- Responsible for **GUI**, **Functional**, **Regression Testing**, **Retesting** & **System Testing**.
- Involved in Compatibility Testing using Browser Stack.
- Involved in writing **Automation Test scripts** using **Selenium with Java**.
- Involved in creating new Page Object Classes & Test Case classes (TestNG).
- Attended **Project meetings** and interacted with other team members to resolve the problems.
- Involved in **UAT Support**

# **Junior QA Engineer,** Evincere Software Solutions 01/2018 – 07/2019 | Pune, India

- Involved in designing Test cases based on S.R.S and Test Plan.
- Involved in Executing Tests and **analyzing results** as per client requirements.
- **Detecting the bugs** and classifying them based on the **severity** and **reporting**.
- **Regression testing** is performed on every new build of the application.
- Involved in **UAT Support**.